Konstantinos Patlatzoglou, Ph.D.

Thessaloniki, Greece

4 26/02/1992 **8** +30 6945940517

■ konspatl@gmail.com

konspatl.github.io

in linkedin.com/in/konspatl/

pithub.com/konspatl

R ORCID:0000-0002-5888-8490

About

Computer scientist with a background in AI, Neuroscience and Biomedical Engineering. During the past 10 years, my experience has focused on research and development of machine learning models for neurophysiological signal analysis. Currently, I'm interested in exploring machine learning methods for scientific discovery and clinical applications.

Experience

2017 - 2022 University of Kent - Machine Learning Researcher

- Researched and developed deep learning-based EEG models for automated, end-to-end, real-time monitoring of the depth of anesthesia.

Skills: • Python (*Tensorflow*) • EEG Analysis (*MNE*) • Digital Signal Processing

• Machine Learning • Deep Learning • Research Methods • Project Management

2017 – 2021 University of Kent - Teaching Assistant

- Preparation, teaching, and marking of undergraduate modules in Computer Science (Part Time).

Skills: • Teaching • Written and Spoken Communication

2015 – 2016 Universitat Pompeu Fabra - Neuroinformatics Researcher

- Researched and developed machine learning models (GLM) for understanding the relation between auditory and neuronal representations during music-induced emotions.

Skills: • NeuroInformatics • Audio Signal Processing • Cognitive Science

Education

2017 – 2022 **Ph.D. in Computer Science** - University of Kent

Thesis title: Deep Learning for Electrophysiological Investigation and Estimation of Anesthetic-Induced Unconsciousness.

2015 – 2016 M.Sc. in Sound and Music Computing - Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Grade: 8.53/10

Thesis title: Neural and Music Correlates of Music-Evoked Emotions.

2010 – 2015 **B.Sc. in Informatics** - Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

Grade: 8.69/10 (First Class Honours)

Thesis title: A study of causal interactions during music listening based on EEG signals using estimates of nonlinear correlations.

Areas of Proficiency

- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- NeuroInformatics and Computational Neuroscience

- Digital Signal Processing
- Teaching
- · Sound and Music Perception and Cognition

Skills

Languages

Greek (*Native*), English (*Proficiency*)

Coding

Python, Java, Matlab, C

ML Libraries

Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras

Misc.

MS Office, LTEX, Unix Shell, Git, Slurm

Activities and Interests

- Biomedical Engineering Cognitive Science and Psychology
- Music Perception and Cognition

- Evolutionary Biology
- Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs)
- Music Composition and Production

Teaching

2017 - 2021

Introduction to Object-Oriented Programming

2017 - 2019

Advanced Object-Oriented Programming

2019 - 2021

Data Structures and Algorithms

2019 - 2020

Agile Development and Software Security

2018 - 2020

Computing Theory and Concurrent Programming

Research Publications

- Patlatzoglou, K. (2022). Deep learning for electrophysiological investigation and estimation of anesthetic-induced unconsciousness (Doctoral dissertation, University of Kent,). Retrieved from https://kar.kent.ac.uk/97272/
- Patlatzoglou, K., Chennu, S., Gosseries, O., Bonhomme, V., Wolff, A., & Laureys, S. (2020). Generalized Prediction of Unconsciousness during Propofol Anesthesia using 3D Convolutional Neural Networks. In 2020 42nd annual international conference of the ieee engineering in medicine & biology society (embc) (Vol. 2020-July, pp. 134–137). Odoi:10.1109/EMBC44109.2020.9175324
- Patlatzoglou, K., Chennu, S., Boly, M., Noirhomme, Q., Bonhomme, V., Brichant, J.-F., ... Laureys, S. (2018). Deep Neural Networks for Automatic Classification of Anesthetic-Induced Unconsciousness. In Lecture notes in computer science (including subseries lecture notes in artificial intelligence and lecture notes in bioinformatics) (Vol. 11309 LNAI, pp. 216-225). Odoi:10.1007/978-3-030-05587-5_21

Grants and Awards

2017 - 2020

Postgraduate research scholarship grant awarded by the University of Kent

2017 - 2021

Conference and summer school attendance grants awarded by the University of Kent

Conferences and Workshops

Sep 2020	Pattern Recognition in Neuroimaging (PRNI) Summer School, Vienna, Austria
Jul 2020	42 nd Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC), Montreal, Canada Invited Talk: Generalized Prediction of Unconsciousness during Propofol Anesthesia using 3D
	Convolutional Neural Networks
May 2020	Brain, Cognition, Emotion and Music (BCEM) Conference, Kent, UK
Nov 2019	Studying Consciousness in the Electrical Brain - Luminous Workshop, Oxford, UK Poster Presentation: Classification and Regression Analysis of Anesthetic States using Electroencephalography and Deep Learning
Jul 2019	3 rd International Summer School on Deep Learning, Warshaw, Poland
Jun 2019	$\ensuremath{\mathrm{I}}^{\mathrm{st}}$ Interdisciplinary Research on Brain Network Dynamics (Brandy) Summer School, Terzolas, Italy
Dec 2018	11 th International Conference on Brain Informatics, Arlington, Texas, US Invited Talk: Deep Neural Networks for Automatic Classification of Anesthetic-Induced Unconsciousness
Sep 2018	Complex Systems Society (CCS) Conference, Thessaloniki, Greece Invited Talk: Classification Analysis of Levels of Consciousness under Anesthesia, using Electroencephalography and Deep Learning Techniques
Sep 2017	International Symposium on Performance Science (ISPS), Reykjavik, Iceland Poster Presentation: Neural and Music Correlates of Music-Evoked Emotions